

## **Contact information**

- Tropavænget 38, Næstved 4700,Denmark
- *▶* 71882266
- ramu0225@gmail.com Linkedin Codepen Github

### **Personal Info**

I am a self-motivated, dedicated, fun, outgoing, sports persons, like to make friends. In free time like to spend time with my family & friends. My hobbies are playing cricket, football and indoor games.

### IT Skills

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, React(JSX), C, VHDL, Bootstrap, Linux/Windows, MS Office, Git, VS-code, Matlab

## Certification

Responsive Web Design.
JavaScript & Data Structures
Front End Libraries

### Languages

Telugu: Mother tongue

Hindi : Native English : Fluent Danish : Basic level

Nationality : Indian DOB : 05/08/1980

## **Professional Profile**

Currently I am looking for a position in front-end developer, as i am passionate about programming & have many years of professional experience in the field of engineering and various SW/HW technologies. I have strong technical skills as well as excellent analytical abilities & good communication skills, enabling me to interact with a wide range of clients. I am eager to be challenged in order to grow & improve my IT skills.

## **Work Experience**

**Production Engineer** | **DFD A/S**, St.heddinge, Denmark

2019 - 2020

- Creating new features, functionality and capabilities on the e-Commerce sites using JavaScript/JSX, Ajax, SASS and JSON.
- Developed app integration with REST API, social media logins, payment processors, and other services.
- Designing and implementing HTML email templates and newsletters for marketing campaigns.

#### 2012-2018

- Responsible for Production flow, Controlling & Troubleshooting the problems held by the automation machines.
- Planning process improvements to effectively utilize equipment and materials to maximize production.
- Develop operational strategies to achieve production and Costumer requirement in everyday life.
- Identify unsafe operations & practices and report the same to Manager immediately.
- Responsible for developing and validating new QC methods for the Packaging.

# **Project Engineer | Bharat Electronic Limited**, *Hyderabad*, *India*.

2005 - 2007

- Expertise in Testing and Integration of Multi Beam Transmitting unit and Airborne Power amplifiers for communication system.
- Integrating the RF front end with receiver processor. RF front end included components to extract and synchronize pulse and frequency parameters for further processing in the receiver processor.
- Testing of mixed signal PCBs which involved both Analog section and Digital sections on the same board.
- Interaction with the Customers, involved in technical documentation and Seminars

## **Internship** | **Bharat** Electronic Limited, *Hyderabad*, *India*.

2003 - 2004

- Testing and integration of sub-modules like RF switching circuits, filters, LNAs, dual directional coupler, Antennae, High Voltage Power Supplies(up to 4KV).
- Knowledge in CDMA, GSM, Handovers, TCP / IP protocol, fading, source & channel coding.
- Expertise in technical equipments like Network Analyzer, Spectrum Analyzer, Logic Analyzer, Pattern generator, Oscilloscope etc

## **Education**

## M.S in System-on-Chip | Lund University, Sweden.

2007 - 2010

- Digital & Analog-IC design, Structured VLSI, IC Project & verification, Advance A/D-D/A, Embedded Systems, Radio.
- Reconfigurable UMTS filter for IC Project was designed (RTL to GDSII), verified and executed on FPGA with grade 4 out of 5 at LTH.
- Programs like Digital IC design & Structured VLSI are compiled with grade 4 out of 5 at LTH.
- Designed & verified Power Aspects of 2D-Discrete Cosine Transform, using 130nm & 65nm CMOS technology as Master's Thesis.

# **B.Tech** in Electronics & Communication | **AEC**, *Hyderabad*, *India*.

1999 - 2003

- Reconfigurable UMTS filter for IC Project was designed (RTL to GDSII), verified and executed on FPGA with grade 4 out of 5 at LTH.
- Programs like Digital IC design & Structured VLSI are compiled with grade 4 out of 5 at LTH.
- Designed & verified Power Aspects of 2D-Discrete Cosine Transform, using 130nm & 65nm CMOS technology as Master's Thesis.